Joseph Emmanuel

Full Stack Web Developer

• 4-2314, rue Parthenais, Montreal QC, H1M 2W3

(514) 893-9188

joseph.emmanuel@outlook.com

LinkedIn

⍃

m

()

A⊉

GitHub

English, Malayalam, Kannada

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages:

JavaScript, MySQL, jQuery, PHP, Java, C#, Python, C, C++,

Frameworks:

Laravel 8, Angular, Node.js, Apache, ASP.NET Core, React

IDE:

VS Code, Eclipse, Visual Studio, IntelliJ IDEA, MATLAB, Anaconda, SSMS

Design Patterns:

MVC, Singleton, observer design

Databases:

MySQL, PostgreSQL, MSSQL

Operating system:

Windows (7/8/10), Linux kali, Tails

Services:

Docker, Mail-SMTP, IIS, Apache

Version-control system:

Git, GitHub, Bitbucket, TFS

Project management tools:

Trello, Asana

PROFILE

Hard-working and enthusiastic professional with more than 3 years of experience and a reliable knowledge of application development, web platform development, and content design using **PHP**, **C#**, **Laravel 8** and **SQL**. Aiming to leverage my skills to successfully fill the full-stack web developer role at your company.

EXPERIENCE

WEB APPLICATION DEVLOPER

Intuitive Web System, Bangalore, India

2017 - 2018

- Design, build, or maintain web Applications
- Collect user Feedback
- Create database modules
- Solve bugs and run on server
- Implement CI/CD Modules

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Unilog content solutions, Mysore, India

2015 - 2016

- Maintain understanding of current web apps.
- Work programming practices through teamwork.
- Develop or validate test routines
- Schedules run test cases
- Run Test modules.

SOFTWARE TRAINEE

Softend Software Solutions, Kannur, Kerala

2012

- Perform direct web content changes.
 - Manage database content.
- Run sample project in different systems.
- Write reports on meetings.
- Replay to the emails from customer.

_ _ _ .

EDUCATION

Programming And Web Technologies

ISI - L'INSTITUT SUPÉRIEUR D'INFORMATIQUE, Montreal, QC (2019-present)

Computer Science and Engineering Master of Technology

VTU-Bangalore, India (2017)

Computer Science and Engineering Bachelor of Technology

CUFE - Bangalore, India (2014)

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Sous chef

NextDoor Pub & Grill, Montreal, QC 2019 - Present

- Assure quality and cleanliness of the food.
- Ensure freshness of food and ingredients.
- Pay attention to detail when sending out a food item.

REFERENCES ARE AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST

PROJECTS

Whistler - | PHP, Laravel 8, MySOL and Socialite

- Job application tracking system for the students in collage or individual
- I worked with a team of 5 people my work was to complete the backend and implement GitHub, Google and Facebook authentication API.
- Link: Whistler

Courier Services | C#, XML, MSSOL, TFS, Azure, .net Core

- Vendors can schedule pickup for courier services up on request from user
- I worked in a team of two people working as a full stack developer. My work was to design, implement and take user experience in account to improve the quality of the application

Data Gathering | Java. MvSOL

- According to the user needs the application can generate dummy data for website development as test data
- My work was to complete the database design and validation that required by the development team and check the data coming from the system and run necessary test cases.

Loan Prediction - | Python, Anaconda, Pandas, Matplotlib

- According to the input data the prediction will be produced if
- they are met the criteria.
- I worked alone as a hobby project idea I found online.
- Link: Loan Prediction

DEUHGA - | MATLAB

- Users can encrypt information in a more secure way
- I worked alone to create an algorithm that can encrypt data using hybrid genetic algorithm
- Link

ToDo list App - | PHP, HTML5, CSS3, MySQL, XAMPP

- Users can create to-do list for their daily routine
- I worked in a group of two people and I worked on both front-end and back-end
- Link : <u>To-do List App</u>

Social Sign App - | PHP, HTML5, CSS3, MySOL, XAMPP

- Users can create to-do list for their daily routine
- I worked in a group of two people and I worked on both front-end and back-end
- Link: Social Sign App